<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on Mario S.O</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on Mario S.O</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 15:39:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mariodev.xyz/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Overcrowded Landscape of JavaScript Frameworks</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/overcrowded/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 15:39:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/overcrowded/</guid><description>JavaScript has come a long way since its inception as a simple scripting language for the web. Today, it is used for a wide range of purposes, from front-end web development to building mobile apps and even desktop applications.
One area where JavaScript has seen particularly rapid growth is in the realm of frameworks. A JavaScript framework is a set of pre-written code that provides a structure for building web applications, making it easier and faster to develop complex applications.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Nuances of Harmful Behavior: Evil vs. Ignorance and Arrogance</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/evilness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 21:29:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/evilness/</guid><description>When it comes to harm and suffering caused by others, it can be tempting to label certain individuals as &amp;ldquo;evil.&amp;rdquo; However, the concept of evil is often used as a catch-all term to describe anyone who causes harm, without necessarily understanding the motivations or thought processes behind their actions. In reality, there are many different factors that can contribute to harmful behavior, and it is important to consider these nuances when trying to understand and address negative actions.</description></item></channel></rss>