<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>huff on Mario S.O</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/tags/huff/</link><description>Recent content in huff on Mario S.O</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 12:00:02 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mariodev.xyz/tags/huff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Day16 - They see me huffing, they hatin'</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day16/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 12:00:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day16/</guid><description>Hehe sorry, but I can&amp;rsquo;t stop playing with huff, It is cool when you start to be able to fix your own mistakes, I think that&amp;rsquo;s a point in which you are starting to understand new stuff.
So today I bring two more challenges from the repo I shared in a previous post.
Non-Payable The task is to write within the MAIN macro, huff code that reverts if ether is sent with the transaction.</description></item><item><title>Day14 - Moar huffing</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day14/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 17:23:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day14/</guid><description>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get too much done today, made a very hard and sad decision and&amp;hellip; well, I needed to rest and take some time for myself.
So I can only show what I did today, which is not much, and actually has been between today and yesterday.
More huff challenges I was only able to finish the Multiply challenge from the repo I shared in the previous post.
he task is to write within the MAIN macro below, a function named multiply that takes in 2 uint256s, and returns their product.</description></item><item><title>Day13 - Huff, learning &amp; bonuses</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day13/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 08:51:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day13/</guid><description>Yooooo, first of all I want to thank anyone reading this, it keeps me motivated knowing that there is someone out there reading my posts so, thank you!
Shoutout to @0xMackenzieM who talked to me via DM giving me some feedback on my approach with this blog. If I ever get nearly half on the knowledge he has, don&amp;rsquo;t doubt a single second that I will pay it forward.
Now to the huff stuff.</description></item></channel></rss>