<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>chatting on Mario S.O</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/tags/chatting/</link><description>Recent content in chatting on Mario S.O</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 09:27:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.mariodev.xyz/tags/chatting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Day X - Rejected</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/dayx/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 09:27:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/dayx/</guid><description>As terrible as a day could get. I was rejected for an internship at Nethermind, and it was the simplest interview imaginable – just a casual technical chat where I was asked about various technical topics.
I was extremely nervous at the beginning and messed up simple questions like &amp;ldquo;How does a reentrancy attack work?&amp;rdquo; and even &amp;ldquo;Explain how a binary search works.&amp;rdquo; When I was asked about the differences between Proof of Work and Proof of Stake, I did well.</description></item><item><title>Day18 - Preparing for the next challenge</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 12:52:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day18/</guid><description>Keep the job hunt going Hi everyone, got some semi-good news, let me break them down.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently applying for a job, this was my idea at the start of this blog project, I want this blog to be the most valuable resource in terms of veracity and an actual day to day journey of a guy with experience in programming and web3 but a total noob in the security space, and how he managed to get a job in the security space.</description></item><item><title>Day15 - Impressive guy &amp; Job hunting</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day15/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 12:33:53 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day15/</guid><description>Damn&amp;hellip; Today found out about @IAm0x52 and this tweet he published a few days ago tweet
Went on and read some of his reports using solodit by filtering the finder field writing 0x52 and I was really impressed by the amount of bugs he found.
I wonder if I will be able to take private audits in a year, that&amp;rsquo;d be a dream come true to be honest, really looking forward to be auditing as my day job.</description></item><item><title>Day09 - Busy af...</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day09/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 15:44:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day09/</guid><description>Today I managed to finish the first challenge of EVM Through CTFs completely, I&amp;rsquo;m now going through a pretty tough one that seems like it is going to be quite a good learning moment, so be sure I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting about it.
Then I met a friend and we kept chatting until 21:30, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty tired now but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to get some sleep and then get back to work tomorrow.</description></item><item><title>Day07 - One of those days</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day07/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 09:17:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day07/</guid><description>Can&amp;rsquo;t share much today, I had such a busy day today that I could only dedicate 1 hour to my learning journey.
Still, managed to discover a new site that perfectly fits my needs for now: EVM Through CTFs
I will go through the first challenge tomorrow and hopefully finish it by the end of the day so I can write about it in the next post.</description></item><item><title>Day01 - The Journey Begins</title><link>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 04:10:05 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.mariodev.xyz/day01/</guid><description>Everything starts here Today will officially be my first day on my journey into becoming a full time smart contract auditor.
It is not my actual first day, maybe the 5th or 6th, but this first days served for a couple of things.
Trainning my algortihm The other day I saw the importance of sinknig yourself into the topic you are trying to learn. In this case, Twitter is the way I started to embed myself into the world of smart contract auditing, following a bunch of well-known auditors and people in the space.</description></item></channel></rss>